MUHAMAD AFIQ ROSLI

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

afig rosli@live.com

) +6737117694

ABOUT ME

Strong sense of resolve to finish available tasks at hand. Gained a year plus of industry experience within my fields while studying for my degree (Computer Science). Further, enhance my programming competency by building web applications following the JAMstack approach.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

Laksamana College of Business, Brunei Darussalam 2021

Achieved Upper Second-Class Honours (2:1) in Computer Science

COMPUTING FOUNDATION

Solent University, Southampton, England 2017

Achieved Merits

SKILLS

JAMstack

Firebase

VueJS 2

VuetifyJS

Laravel

Java

Android

Algolia

ASP.NET Core & MVC

MariaDB

Microsoft Azure

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | *HUETECH Enterprise* | *Jun 2020 - Present* JAMSTACK developer utilising Vue.js & Firebase. Built a Content-Management-System (CMS) platform for the Ministry of Culture, Youth and Sports to manage digital artworks.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | Grominda SDN BHD | Sep 2019 - Jul 2020 Holds two responsibilities; a website developer & interim project manager. The website technologies used were PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, MySQL & Microsoft Azure. The project management approach was through Agile Scrum. Supervised multiple interns and delegating works. Actively communicate with relevant departments to ensure business logic are met within the platform (Plus EXP).

INTERNSHIP

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | *Grominda SDN BHD* | *Jun 2019 - Sep 2019* Maintaining Plus EXP website, a platform to help people connect with their prospective employers. Laravel framework was used.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

BICTA PLUS BOOTCAMP | SUHBE CO | Dec 2020 - Present

Be part of the Bootcamp to jumpstart Brunjar's development; a HUETECH Enterprise product. Brunjar is a marketplace platform that aims to help individuals & small companies to start selling online and build communities. Built it to be a Vue SPA (Single Page Application) integrated with Firebase.

VOLUNTEER | *MSME Festival 2019* | *Mar 2019*

Performed as an usher, receptionist, & public relations with the vendors. Execute orders given by supervisors and divide task amongst ourselves. Ensuring we do our tasks as instructed and summaries what was done for the next group in-line taking our role. Team building importance is understood to make the event flows smoothly.

LANGUAGES

Malay (Native) English (Fluent) Japanese (Novice)

DRIVING LICENSE

Driving license category Class 3

LINKS

Portfolio:

https://afigrosli.github.io/

REFERENCE

WAZINI AWANG

Grominda SDN BHD T: +6737121045 E: wazini.awang@gromindagroup.com

COURSES

PROJECT MANAGEMENT | Grominda SDN BHD | Jun 2020

ART OF PERSUASIVE PRESENTATIONS | *Articulation* | *Oct 2019*

HOBBIES

Programmed tools for my own use i.e. Finance web app & Literature Review web app. The latter project was to managed my literature reading for my FYP (Final Year Project). Progressively increase my coding style to follow the KISS (Keep It Short and Simple) & DRY (Don't Repeat Yourself) principles. Recenlty starts delving into unit testing within the JavaScript ecosystem to produce more stable code. Readable code benefits the whole party involved within the development.